Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Ron de Pear papers, 1986-1997 and undated RL.11511
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Ron de Pear papers
1986-1997 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
De Pear, Ron
RL.11511
3.0 Linear Feet
Advertising executive and media specialist with J. Walter Thompson Company's London Office and JWT Europe. Collection includes correspondence, research reports, articles, presentations and other printed materials. Companies represented include CIA Media, De Beers, Nestle, Ogilvy & Mather, Revlon and Rimmel. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
Advertising executive and media specialist with J. Walter Thompson Company's London Office and JWT Europe.
JWT Sydney 1970-1976; Assistant Media Director, JWT London 1976-1984; Media Director, JWT London 1984; JWT Worldwide Board 1992; Chairman, JWT Worldwide Media Group 1995-1997; Managing Partner, Mindshare Worldwide, 1998-2000; Chairman, CIA International Media Unit, 2000-2002; Global Development Director, ECI Media Management, circa 2013-2015.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Ron de Pear papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. Bill Lane papers; J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Media Resources and Research Department records; J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office. Paul-G. Siebel papers; J. Walter Thompson Company. Ronald B. Kaatz papers
Collection Overview
Collection includes correspondence, research reports, articles, presentations and other printed materials. Companies represented include CIA Media, De Beers, Nestle, Ogilvy & Mather, Revlon and Rimmel. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising -- Great Britain; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain; Advertising executives -- Great Britain; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Nestlé Company; De Beers Consolidated Mines; Revlon, inc.; De Pear, Ron
- Ron de Pear papers, 1986-1997 and undated; 1
  - Adfacts--Asia, 1997; 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Adfacts--Europe, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Adfacts--Latin America, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Adfacts--North America, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Adspend Today, Adspend Tomorrow, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Aegis Group plc, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Board meeting, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Body Language in Business (Wendy Gordon), undated (Box 1)
  - Brand Stewardship Wired (Jane Ostler), undated (Box 1)
  - Brands Across Borders (Judie Lannon), 1990 (Box 1)
  - Brands and the Media Future (Mandy Pooler), undated (Box 1)
  - CIA Group plc, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1990-1997; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - De Beers/JWT Inter-Country Comparison of Media Performance (Tim Drysdale), 1991 (Box 1)
  - Detroit meeting, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Differences by Market (Antoine Blouet), undated (Box 2)
  - Disappearing Frontiers? The Changing Media Scene in Europe (D. Byles), 1993 (Box 2)
  - Effective frequency, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Elizabeth Arden Cosmetics Competitive Media Analysis--Asia/Pacific, 1993 (Box 2)
  - The European Consumer in the Year 2000 (Judie Lannon), undated (Box 2)
  - A European Media Perspective, 1989 (Box 2)
  - European Media Trends, 1994 (Box 2)
  - The Future of Brand Communication, undated (Box 2)
  - A Guide to Media Planning (Tim Drysdale), undated (Box 2)
  - Henley Centre TV93 Report, 1993 (Box 2)
  - High Definition Media Planning (Phil Gullen), 1991 (Box 2)
  - International Media Division status report, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Introduction to the UK media scene, 1989 (Box 2)
  - JWT Account Plan, 1989 (Box 2)
  - JWT Europe--Client List, 1994 (Box 2)
  - JWT Europe--Major Media Issues, 1992 (Box 2)
  - JWT Europe--Media 1990 Office Assessment (Box 2)
  - JWT Europe--Media One Year On, 1990 (Box 2)
  - JWT Europe--Media Operational Plans, 1989 (Box 2)
  - JWT Europe--Presentation, 1990 (Box 2)
  - JWT Europe--Presentation Bank, 1994 (Box 3)
  - JWT Europe--Review of Overseas Buying, 1989 (Box 3)
  - JWT Media Person's Handbook, 1990 (Box 3)
  - JWT Medialink Europe, undated (Box 3)
  - JWT/Ogilvy cooperation, 1995-1996 (Box 3)
  - JWT Toronto Office media staff, undated (Box 3)
  - Kellogg UK account plan, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Kodak Media, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Managing Media, undated (Box 3)
  - Marketing Brands in the Year 2000, undated (Box 3)
  - Media--Country Differences, undated (Box 3)
  - Media Department Germany, undated (Box 3)
  - Media Glossary, undated (Box 3)
  - Media in Europe, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Media Inflation, undated (Box 3)
  - Media Insight International, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Media Odyssey (Lotus Notes application), 1997 (Box 3)
  - Media Overspill in Europe, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Media quotes, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Media planning presentation, undated (Box 4)
  - Media reports, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Media Role in the JWT 3-Year Plan, 1992-1993; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Media: The New Creative Frontier? (Burt Manning), 1989 (Box 4)
  - Meeting the Challenge of Asia/Pacific Best Media Value, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Nestle Eastern Europe Media Presentation, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Outlook for Advertising Media Placement, undated (Box 4)
  - Overseas media presentation, undated (Box 4)
  - Perspective for the 1990s (Antony O'Reilly, Heinz), undated (Box 4)
  - Poland--JWT Parintex Warsaw, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Preface (Predictive Formula for Audience Coverage Estimation) Plus, 1990 (Box 4)
  - A Question of Priorities (Ogilvy & Mather), 1994 (Box 4)
  - Review of JWT's Media Buying Position in Europe, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Revlon new business opportunity, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Rimmel Agency Briefing (Margaret Donnelly, Coty), 1996 (Box 4)
  - Rise of Media Independents and Brokers in Europe, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Saban, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Shell/CIA Media Brief, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Some Facts About J. Walter Thompson Europe, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Some Facts About JWT in Europe, 1989 (Box 5)
  - South Africa, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Status of Commercial Television in Europe, 1991 (Box 5)
  - Thinking Global, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Thompson Total Targeting, 1999 (Box 5)
  - Total Branding, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Total Branding Insights, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Understanding the Basics of Media (Sue Ide-Smith), undated (Box 5)
  - Viewpoint East (Neomedion Ltd), 1991 (Box 5)
  - Worldwide Executive Group Meeting (WWEG) reference article packet, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Zenith Media reports, 1996 (Box 5)